Hello friends, my name is Anil Rajpat
and today I am presenting to you an
excellent product of SBI Life Insurance launched in 2023, which is called
Smart Life Time Saver. This is such a plan
where you will get lifelong benefits for 100 years.
You have to make premium payment here for only 10 years, 12 years
or 15 years,
but your income should start coming from the seventh year. If
you pay the premium,
you will start getting income every year from the seventh year itself.
For example, if you pay lakhs, then you will
start getting around ₹0,000 from the seventh year and
after the premium payment term is completed,
you will get approximately one lakh rupees every year. You will
also get around ₹ crore on life time and maturity,
tax free and the insurance cover will
also last for the entire 100 years. So this is an excellent
product.
I am presenting you the complete information about this product in detail.
If you like my video, then my
Anil Rajput Triple FS must like,
share, subscribe and share this
video with as many people as possible
so that they too can avail this excellent plan of SBI.  To
avail maximum benefits, life insurance was
established in the year 2000, 23 years
ago. SBI Life Insurance has
around 1000 offices spread across India. There are
22000 employees who work on salary
and around 1.25 lakh agents
who are providing you services.
SBI Life Insurance is
one of the largest companies in India. Its market share is
more than 10% and this year its growth
in the first quarter is 45%.
If we talk about the AUM (
Asset Under Management) of SBI, then this company is worth
Rs 328 lakh crore. If we talk about the solvency ratio of the company, then it has a
solvency ratio of 2.15. Solvency ratio
means that in simple language,
suppose you pay a premium of Rs 1 in SBI Life, then
SBI Life has
Rs 1 to give you a claim, so this is a great option.  It has a good
solvency ratio and is also a great company.
Their claim settlement
ratio is also quite good here. I
give official information in many places that
if I talk about the last two months, i.e. August 2023, then the
market share of LIC has
decreased from about 9%.
Loss of market share is a big thing.
LIC has always been the number one company in India because it has been
in the market since 1956, but right now there is a
lot of competition in the market. There are 24 life insurance
companies, 23 private life insurance
companies, SBI is also a private life
insurance company, so while
LIC's market share is decreasing,
SBI has achieved a growth of
45% in the first quarter of this financial year.
Where SBI is growing from 45%,
brother, LIC's share is decreasing a bit.
Compared to private companies, let's talk
about this product. SBI
Life Smart Life Time Saver. The
main feature of this product is that it lasts for
100 years.  There are three options for paying premiums. You
can pay premium for 10 years,
12 years, or 15 years. The
policy will run for 100 years.
In this policy, you start
getting guaranteed income as soon as the premium payment term is completed.
This is a life time
policy. You also get a cash bonus from the seventh year.
If you want to deposit the
survival benefit, cash bonus, and the
income you get every year instead of withdrawing it every year, you can
also invest it in a cumulative policy. You will also get maturity in this policy
and your insurance
cover will also remain for 100 years. You will also get income tax benefit
in this policy. Who can buy this policy? Anyone from a
30-day-old child
to 55 years of age can purchase this policy. You can
purchase this policy with a minimum premium of Rs. 30.
You
can also pay annual premium. If you wish to pay premium
in semi-annual, quarterly, and monthly mode, you can do so. The
policy
will run for 100 years and the premium  The payment
options are 10 years, 12 years, 15 years. How is the guaranteed
survival income calculated, which you get for a
guaranteed lifetime after the completion of the premium payment term?
It is calculated on the basis of premium and
not on the basis of age. This is a good
thing, friend, on the basis of premium. How will it be calculated? If your
premium is between Rs 30,000 to Rs 49,000, then your
premium will be between Rs 50,000 to Rs 99,000, then your premium will be between Rs 1 lakh to Rs 99,000
and the premium will be between Rs 2 lakh and above.
How will you get guaranteed income according to that? Suppose
your premium payment term is 10 years.
Look here, in the picture, the percentage written as 2.25 is the
basic sum. Understand it this way, understand the
premium. So, suppose you are
paying a premium of Rs 1 lakh, then
you will get a guaranteed income of Rs 2500. If your
premium payment term is 12 years,
then you will get Rs.  You will get a guaranteed income of Rs 77500 and
if you select a premium payment term of 15 years,
then you will get a
guaranteed income of Rs 335000 if your premium is
between Rs 0000 to Rs 49000 but suppose
your premium is Rs 1 lakh, let us understand with a sample
that the premium is more than Rs 1 lakh, then if
you pay premium for 15 years then
you will get a guaranteed income of Rs 40000, if you
pay for 12 years then you will get a guaranteed
income of Rs 32500 and if you pay premium for 10 years then you will
also get a cash bonus of Rs 2500000, the company will declare the cash bonus every year,
you will get the cash bonus accordingly, let us see now how the
cash bonus will be, the cash bonus will
start coming to you from the end of the seventh year, the
rate of cash bonus is declared by the company every year,
SP Insurance will declare every year
that I am giving cash bonus, at what rate am I
giving it into basic sum or basic sum
So, suppose you have Rs 10 lakh and suppose
they declare the rate of cash bonus
at Rs 4, then you will get a bonus of Rs 0,000 plus the
guaranteed income that you are getting will come to you, so
both the cash bonus and the guaranteed income
together will keep going to your account through NEFT every year.
Now, if you want to deposit or accumulate the
cash bonus and guaranteed income that you are getting every year,
you do not have to do it now, then
you can do it and after that, when you have a
requirement, you have been given the option in the information to the company
that how much will be your insurance cover, how much will be the
death benefit, then the insurance cover will be from
15 times to 11 times of the premium you pay, depending on the age.
Suppose
you purchase a policy in the name of a child who is 3 months old or 6
months old, then he will get an
insurance cover of Rs 15 lakh against Rs 1 lakh. If someone is 35
years old, then he will get 13 times the insurance cover, it is
written here.  So you will
get an insurance cover of 13 lakhs. If someone is 55 years old,
then they will get an insurance cover of ₹ lakhs. From this
section, let us understand
how this product will actually work. There is a
person who is purchasing a policy for his nine year old child.
He is
paying a premium of ₹ lakhs for 15 years. The
policy will run for 100 years. So what
benefits will he get? From the seventh year, you will
start getting a cash bonus of ₹ 9000. You can see the picture,
everything has been mentioned there.
After that, you will see that your cash bonus keeps
increasing from time to time, so your
bonus will become ₹ 69000. By the end of 30 years, your
bonus will go up to ₹
71500. Along with this,
you are also getting a guaranteed survival
benefit. So, how much will you get for the first 30
years? ₹ 0000, after that you will get ₹
0000 and after that you will get a cash
bonus of ₹ 27500 and at the end
How much money will you get on maturity 9 crore
230000 You will get maturity,
see in this picture how much you got Survival Income Total
32500 Bonus how much you got 59
56500 Match you got 9 crore
2300 Total if you add all this then you
got 10 crore 91000 One lakh in 15 years
How much are you getting in front of 15 lakhs You are getting 10
crore rupees
In this policy of SBI Life Insurance,
how much will your insurance cover be from day one
Basic sum of 85000 lakhs on which all these
calculations will be done and if you suppose the
customer dies at the age of 60 years, when he
dies, how much will the family get
4494 as death benefit because the
insurance keeps increasing with time,
so here you have to pay limited premium, pay for
10 years, 12 years or 15 years, in this
way you can avail the benefit, in
SBI  I will explain it with the help of illustrations as well. You can
watch the video further. I have taken some sample examples of
different apps. If you pay premium for 10 years,
12 years,
15 years, then how do you get the
benefit, how will you get the calculation? You will get
to see the illustration.
Now let us understand all the benefits of this plan
with the illustration. This
illustration will also be attached to your policy bundle.
When you purchase the policy, there is a
person whose age is 35 years and he has a
son or daughter whose age is 3 years and
he is purchasing the policy in the name of the son
whose age is 9 years. Here he is
paying the premium for 15 years. The policy
will run for 97 years because the policy will run till 3 years or 100 years. The
customer will pay the premium annually. Rs. lakh cash bonus. He will
get the bonus. His basic time seed will be Rs. lakh
and death benefit will be there from the first day.
That will be the
rider of Rs. 85000. He has not made any purchase for the
first year. There will be GST.  Along with this, a
premium of Rs 10500 will be payable. The premium for the remaining 14 years will be
Rs 2250. Now let's see here,
see in the annual premium column number, you are paying Rs 1 lakh each for 15 years.
After that, if you do
not have to pay any premium, then you do
not have to pay any premium. Now there will be a column here, the
column of guaranteed benefit which you will
see here. In this guaranteed benefit
column, you will see that as told, as soon as the
premium payment is complete, you will
start getting an income of Rs 0000, that is,
you will start getting Rs 0000 guaranteed. When will it start?
From the 15th year. Secondly, you have been told
that the cash bonus will come. When will you get the cash bonus?
From the seventh year. So, in the seventh year, you
will see that here you
started getting a cash bonus of Rs 19000. Look at column number 12,
where you started getting Rs 19000, that is,
you paid Rs 59000 and you got it
back from your pocket.  You only lost Rs 41,000. This is
also a big thing that you are
getting good returns here.
You don't have to wait long from the seventh year. There are six premiums for the
seventh year, so you are
getting the money in full. So now if you add up here,
look at column number 15, where you will
add up columns number 4 and 12. If you add up, you will
see how much total
amount you will get. You are getting Rs 59 from seven to 15 years,
but if
you
look from the 16th year, from the end of 15 years, you will
get Rs 99,000. Because the
guaranteed income of Rs 0,000 is coming to you plus the
cash bonus of Rs 9,000, so the total amount you will get is Rs 99,000. And
this will keep coming for your child for life. It will start
coming for life. If your child
is 3 years old, he will start getting Rs 59,000 from the age of 10.
And then when he turns 18,
consider him to be around Rs 1 lakh. He will keep getting Rs 9,000 for life.
On maturity,
maturity will also come in the seventh year, it will remain 9 crore 22,
you will also get maturity of 9 crore 22, this is the maturity
column, but you see,
you also get maturity of 9 crore 2300, if suppose at any
time I try to explain it to you by showing in one and two columns,
here you will
see that your insurance cover also
increases with time, if you see the benefit column also, then
it keeps increasing every year,
for example, if the customer is 6 years old, that is,
I understand that if he
dies at the age of 73, if he has a policy term of 70, then his
family members will get Rs 76 lakh 65000 at that time
and he keeps taking Rs 9000 every year,
so you can see this benefit also
and surrender benefit also, if you notice
that you want to surrender at any time, for
example, I will
take the example of 70 here, if you go to surrender at this time, you will
surrender  The column number
is the
medicine number for you, so if you see here in the medicine number
column,
even if you go to surrender at the age of 70, you will get Rs 27900, the
regular income that you were getting was
coming, even after surrendering you are
getting a good income, sorry,
you will get the surrender benefit here, see in column number 13,
which was a huge amount,
75 lakhs, 75 lakhs, you are getting the surrender benefit at the age of
70, here you see this column
where you have also been given the option of surrender,
if you want to surrender at any time,
for example, if you
surrender at the policy term of 76, then you will get Rs 1 crore,
so here you
can understand completely how it will work for you,
I have taken the second example
that there is a 34 year old person and he is purchasing for himself
and here he is paying the premium for only 10 years, the
big thing is that the
good thing about this plan is that this premium is for 10 years  There is an option to pay for 12 years and
15 years, even then you should
see the income here, here
you are getting an income of 0000 because you are
getting a guaranteed income of 77500 plus your bonus is also
being declared, 4500 has become 500 and
here you will start getting an income of 8000 as soon as the premium payment term is completed, so
here you are getting an income of 68000,
you are also getting 89 lakhs on lifetime and maturity,
10 years premium will be paid, the
policy will run for 100 years, the age of the customer is 34 years, if we
take this third example, where you will have to pay for 12 years, then
how will it be, you are getting an
income of 48000, then you will get an income of 80000
and on maturity you will get 1 crore 1
lakh, so if you want to pay the premium for 12 years, then you
can select this one
if your age is 50, if you are 50 years  If you are
10 years old and
want to take a policy for 50 years after paying premium for 10 years, even if you are paying a premium of Rs.1 lakh,
you will still get Rs.4500. If
you notice one thing, whether you pay premium for 15 years or
12 years or 10 years, you are getting an income of Rs.40500,
this one is 8000 or this one is
68000 on 10 years, you are getting around 80000, on
12 years you are
getting 99000 on 15 years, depending on how much premium you pay,
you will
start getting income here and on maturity
you will get Rs.270000 because you have a 50 year
policy term, the
more opportunity you get to grow the money, the bigger the amount you will get, so
you can enjoy it while you are alive, you can enjoy a good
income, you can
enjoy your retirement time, in
this way this
is the illustration of the best plan of this company, which will be beneficial for
your policy bond.  If we also talk about
other features of the policy, then
you get a free look period of 15 days. Suppose you
purchased the policy and did not like it due to any
reason, you can
go to the company within 15 days and return the policy and
get the entire money back. This is called free look
period. In the grace period, you will
also get a grace period of 30 days. If the
premium is due to you and you are
not able to pay it due to some reason, then
you have one month's time. You can pay the premium within one month also.
You will get the benefit
continue. Tax benefit:
You will get tax benefit under section ATC of Income Tax
and your income will be
tax free under 101D. If your premium is ₹ lakh
or less, if the policy has lapsed,
if you have paid two premiums,
if you have paid less than two premiums, if you have paid more than two
premiums, then your
policy will lapse and you will not get any benefit.
But if you have
paid more than two premiums, suppose you have paid three premiums
or five premiums, let us take an example
that 10  If you had to pay five premiums, that is, if you
paid money at 50, then your policy will become
RP. The paid-up benefit will be reduced, which
means that the benefits that you were supposed to get at the rate of ₹1 will
now come at the rate of 50,
but they will definitely come. Talking about surrender benefit, if
you want to surrender this policy, you
can do so. I am
not suggesting that you should surrender it,
but yes, there is a very long policy of 100 years in the future. If
you ever feel like it is in the long term, then
you can do it. But you should never purchase any savings plan
from the point of view of surrender
because if
you surrender early, in just a few years, then there is a
greater possibility of loss.
Talking about the revival period, in this policy,
suppose due to some reason you are not
able to pay the premium, if you are not able to pay for one year, two years, three years, then
there is a revival period of five years, that is,
you can revive your policy by paying three
or four premiums together,
paying late fees, getting a medical checkup done, and getting the
entire
benefit back.  Let's start with the talk
of loan in the policy. In this policy, loan will not be available
because SBI is also a big company
in India and if I compare it
with LIC's Jeevan Umang, will Jeevan Umang be a
good plan or SBI's plan will be
good. I have shown you the comparison of illustration,
so here is its RR
comparison. RR means actually
how much power of compound, how much
interest, at what rate of interest are you
getting this money because you do
not understand from the amount, at least which one can be better
for you. So here I have
compared LIC's Jeevan Umang and SBI's
Smart Life that in Jeevan Umang, if
you pay premium for 15 years, then minus
₹ lakh is written, after that
you get a lifetime guaranteed income of ₹ 4000 and you
also get a maturity amount of 1 crore 30
lakh and this interest rate works out to be
6.02 per cent in the entire 100 year policy.
LIC's Jeevan Umang is charging you interest.
If the age of the person is 35 years, the
premium increases every 15 years and he is taking a policy for 100 years, the
premium is ₹1 lakh, the basic
set is ₹1 lakh, the same policy, if the
person purchases this life time policy from SBI, the same premium increases by ₹1 lakh,
so here you will see that I have
written ₹41000 on the seventh year because
you are getting ₹59000 back from the company and
then you are getting a life time income of ₹99000
and you are also getting a maturity of ₹99 lakh 999 99000,
approximately 0.5
CR, so here your error, the
interest rate, comes out to be
6.87, ₹687 is the life time interest and it is an
excellent interest rate, according to me,
such a good error, there are very few products in the industry
whose error in the life time
policy is around 7, that
too tax free, that too with insurance cover, the
product which  The competitor
in the market is LIC's Jeevan Umang. Now
if we compare LIC's Jeevan Umang with this, then
you can see which product will be better for you.
LIC's Jeevan Umang. The age of a customer is 35
years. He pays premium for 15 years. The
policy term will be 65 years. The basic term is
Rs. 1 lakh and we have kept a premium of Rs. 1 lakh.
Here you will see that as soon as 15 years are
completed, you will start getting an income of Rs. 000
and this will be for life time.
You will get an income of Rs. 000 for life time
and on maturity you will get Rs. 1 crore 30,57200.
If we compare this with LIC's Jeevan Umang and
SBI, the age of the customer becoming 35 years has been
kept for 15 years here also
and an option of Rs. 1 lakh has been kept here also and
here you get the death benefit which is the basic
benefit and is kept for Rs. 13 lakh. Now
see here, here for 15 years  Income will
not start coming after this but from the seventh year
you are getting Rs 59000, so
technically money of Rs 41000 is going out of your pocket from the seventh year
and at the age of 15 you are getting Rs 99000, so it is going out
of your pocket, then you are getting an income of Rs 99000 in your
lifetime and on maturity
you are getting Rs 99 lakh,
you are getting this also around Rs 1 crore because Rs
99000 is 9 lakh, so you will get this and Rs 99000 is
also getting this, so out of Rs 1 crore, Rs 000 will be reduced, so
this also becomes a maturity of around Rs 1 crore for you, now if we
calculate the IRR of both, then I think the
interest rate of LIC is 6.02 and the
IRR rate of SBI is around 6.8, so if
you compare it with IRR then
you will understand that
which one can give you more returns in actual, so if
I compare this product then
this  This is an excellent plan. SBI Life
Insurance Company is a big company
of India. As I told you that
this is a company worth Rs 328 lakh crore.
You have many branches here and
you can also avail services. If you want to buy this policy from me
also, then you can contact me
on 9909 403410. In this product,
you make a limited premium payment
but you are getting benefits up to 100 years. You are getting
tax benefits. You are getting
bonus from the seventh year. You are
getting guaranteed income, that too for life time.
Your insurance cover is available for 100 years.
If you are taking a policy for children also, then
you can take a policy for a 30-day old child or a one-month old child, which will
give them life time income. If you are
also looking for retirement for yourself, then
you can plan for tax free retirement.
And if
you want to purchase this policy in H, then you can take
this policy in H as an employer employee also,
if you want to take this policy, then you can take it.  If you
want to take this policy in partnership also, then
you can purchase this policy in partnership also.
If
you want to purchase this policy under MWP Act also, then
you can purchase this policy under MWP Act also.
So if  I may ask whether there is any
other product like this in any other company like Max,
Tata, Bala, ICC, ADC,
if yes then whose plan is better,
where can you get more interest, will you
get more interest in their plan, is this the best, which one will be best for you,
you can contact me for all this information, to
get quick information about insurance,
videos, posters, you can contact my
whatsapp-web